{
    "1":{"question":"Who coined the term 'Internet of Things'?",
"answer":"Kevin Aston"},
"2":{"question":"When was the actual term “Internet of Things” coined?","answer":"1999"},
"3":{"question":"Which layer is used for wireless connection in IoT devices?","answer":"Data link layer is used for Ethernet and wireless connections. The network layer is used for Internet Protocols. The transport layer is used for TCP/UDP protocols and the application layer directly interacts with the application."},
"4":{"question":"The relation between IoT and M2M is ___________","answer":"M2M is the part of IoT"},
"5":{"question":"What is considered the standard length for a MAC Address?","answer":"48 bits or 6 bytes"},
"6":{"question":"At which level does the router operate in the OSI reference model?","answer":"Network"},
"7":{"question":"Full form of MQTT?","answer":"Message Queuing Telemetry Transport"},
"8":{"question":"What does OSI stand for in networking?","answer":"Open System Interconnection "},
"9":{"question":"How many layers does the ISO OSI reference model contain? ","answer":"7"},
"10":{"question":"What is the primary role of a network hub in a network?","answer":"To forward data to all connected devices   "},
"11":{"question":"Which protocol is used to send email messages?   ","answer":" Simple Mail Transfer Protocol (SMTP)"},
"12":{"question":"The size of an IP address in IPv6 is _________","answer":"128bits"},
"13":{"question":"The header length of an IPv6 datagram is ___________","answer":"40bytes"},
"14":{"question":"IPv6 does not use ________ type of address.","answer":" Broadcast"},
"15":{"question":"IP address is 32 bit value which is divided into ______ octets.","answer":"4"},
"16":{"question":"An IoT network is a collection of ______ devices.","answer":"Interconnected"},
"17":{"question":"HTTP stands for ________","answer":"HTTP stands for Hyper Text Transfer Protocol."},
"18":{"question":"UDP stands for ________","answer":"User Datagram Protocol"},
"19":{"question":"Which protocol interacts asynchronously over UDP?","answer":"CoAP"},
"20":{"question":"WSN stands for:","answer":"Wireless Sensor Network"},
"21":{"question":" Standard ports of MQTT are __________","answer":"TCP/IP"},
"22":{"question":"What are the key components of a M2M system?","answer":"Sensors and Wi-Fi"},
"23":{"question":"MQTT is _________ oriented.","answer":"Message"},
"24":{"question":"Which layer is CoAP?","answer":"Application layer"},
"25":{"question":"How many types of message formats are there in HTTP protocol?","answer":"The client and server communication by sending plain text message. The client sends requests to the server and server sends the responses. That is –> Request message, –> Response message."},
"26":{"question":"Which IoT component is responsible for managing device identity and access control?","answer":"Cloud platform"},
"27":{"question":"Which IoT communication protocol is based on publish-subscribe messaging pattern","answer":"MQTT"},
"28":{"question":"Which IoT connectivity technology has the longest range?","answer":"LoRaWAN (Long Range Wide Area Network)"},
"29":{"question":"Which IoT data format is commonly used for representing and exchanging structured data","answer":"JSON (JavaScript Object Notation)"},
"30":{"question":"Which of the following IoT technologies is typically used for short-range, point-to-point communication between devices?","answer":"Zigbee"},
"31":{"question":"Which protocol is commonly used for secure IoT device communication?","answer":"HTTPS"},
"32":{"question":"How does IoT contribute to big data?","answer":"By generating high volume,high velocity data"},
"33":{"question":"Which protocol is specifically designed for constrained devices and networks in the IoT?","answer":"CoAP"},
"34":{"question":"Which IoT communication model is most efficient for devices that require low power consumption?","answer":"Publish-Subscribe"},
"35":{"question":"In IoT, which protocol is known for its low overhead and suitability for constrained devices?","answer":"MQTT"},
"36":{"question":"What is the primary advantage of using IPv6 over IPv4 in IoT?","answer":"Larger Address space"},
"37":{"question":"What distinguishes Bluetooth Low Energy (BLE) from classic Bluetooth in the context of IoT?","answer":"Low power consumption"},
"38":{"question":"UDP and TCP are called ________ protocols:","answer":"Transport"},
"39":{"question":"What does the term 'Thing' refer to in IoT?","answer":"Any object that can be connected to the internet"},
"40":{"question":"The bit length of the IPV4 is _________","answer":"32 bits"},
"41":{"question":"The IPV4 has a ____________ notation for addressing","answer":"Dotted decimals"},
"42":{"question":"The IPV6 has a ____________ notation for addressing","answer":"Hexadecimal"}
}